Finding aid to the International Institute for Girls in Spain records CA.MS.00103
Smith College Archives
- Series II. CORRESPONDENCE
  - Director
    - President, 1912-80; undated (Box 22, Folder 597-601)
    - Treasurer, 1911-41 (Box 22, Folder 602-606)
    - Treasurer, 1942-80; undated (Box 23, Folder 607-612)
  - General
    - Miscellaneous, 1893-1979; undated (Box 23, Folder 613-621)
    - Ilene Avery, 1964-70; undated (Box 23, Folder 622-627)
    - Enriqueta Martin, 1925-39; 1950- 71; undated (Box 23, Folder 628-634)
    - Mary Sweeney, 1963-67; undated (Box 24, Folder 635-651)
- Series III. FINANCIAL
  The records in this series consist of accounts, budget summaries, annual and other forms of financial reports, and topical files on building, donations, rents, salaries, and tuition. None are complete. Some of the records were maintained in Spain by IIGS staff and others by the Treasurer in the United States and are so identified on the folder title list where possible.
  In addition to covering daily operating expenses and annual budgets, the records also contain some information about policies and the IIGS financial relationship with Estudio.
  Related material may be found in the Treasurer's Correspondence - Series II and in the Minutes - Series VIII.
  The records are arranged alphabetically by type and then chronologically within each type.
  - Accounts, IIGS, 1911 (Box 24, Folder 652)
  - Accounts, Spain, 1928-46 (Box 24, Folder 653)
  - Accounts, Spain, 1946-51 (Box 24, Folder 654)
  - Accounts, Spain, Estudio-IIGS, 1952-68 (Box 25, Folder 655-658)
  - Accounts, US, 1948-59 (Box 25, Folder 659)
  - Accounts, US, 1958-62 (Box 25, Folder 660-661)
  - Accounts, US, Stocks, 1958-74 (Box 25, Folder 662-666)
  - Annual and other Financial Reports, 1910-54 (Box 25, Folder 667-674)
  - Annual and other Financial Reports, 1960-81 (Box 26, Folder 675-677)
  - Audits, 1927-31 (Box 26, Folder 678)
  - Budget, Spain, 1967-72 (Box 26, Folder 679-680)
  - Budget Summaries, 1962-66; 1973-80 (Box 26, Folder 681-682)
  - Building Costs, 1910-50; undated (Box 26, Folder 683-684)
  - Donations and Gifts, 1897-1937; 1969-71 (Box 26, Folder 685-686)
  - Rents, 1971-73 (Box 26, Folder 687)
  - Salaries, 1965-77 (Box 26, Folder 688)
  - Tuition Rates, 1914-15 (Box 26, Folder 689)
- Series IV. HISTORICAL MATERIALS AND MEMORABILIA
  This series is divided into four subseries: General, Biography, Reminiscences, and Memorabilia.
  The General historical materials consist of clippings, pamphlets and manuscripts on the history of the Institute, endorsements of Institute activities, and appeals for funds. Biography contains clippings, tributes, memorabilia, and manuscripts by and about some of the major individuals in the history of the Institute such as founders, benefactors, staff, and alumnae. Reminiscences contains transcripts and notes on interviews with alumnae and staff, a manuscript on the Library Science Program, and a set of responses to a questionnaire sent to alumnae. Memorabilia consists of such items as floor plans, diplomas, report cards, a guestbook, invitations, programs, scrapbooks, and school songs from various periods in the Institute's history reflecting activities in Spain and the U.S.
  Within each subseries the material is arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - General
    - Clippings, manuscripts, pamphlets, 1889-l978; undated (Box 26, Folder 690-694)
    - "An Outline History of the International Institute for Girls in Spain, 1877-1980" by Joan C. Ullman (Box 26, Folder 695)
    - Articles and papers by Carmen de Zulueta, 1975-76; undated (Box 26, Folder 696)
    - Activities, Spain: clippings, 1888-1979; undated (Box 26, Folder 697)
    - Activities, U.S.: clippings, 1903-14 (Box 26, Folder 698)
    - Appeals, 1881-1914; undated (Box 26, Folder 699)
    - Endorsements, 1903 (Box 26, Folder 700)
    - Miscellaneous, 1894-1961; undated (Box 26, Folder 701)
  - Biography
    - Catherine Hayden Barbour, tributes,clippings, 1901-02; undated (Box 27, Folder 702)
    - Alice Gordon Gulick
      - Clippings and tributes, 1894-1372; undated (Box 27, Folder 703)
      - Drafts and bibliography for Notable American Women, article by Mary Sweeney, 1962 (Box 27, Folder 704)
      - Memorabilia, 1903; undated (Box 27, Folder 705)
    - William Hooker Gulick: clipping, tribute, 1906; 1912 (Box 27, Folder 706)
    - Enriqueta Martin
      - Autobiographical sketch, 1971 Jun (Box 27, Folder 707)
      - "Espana": manuscript, 1972 Apr 5 (Box 27, Folder 708)
      - "Excursions con el Sr. Giner,1932-33": journal, 1933 Oct (Box 27, Folder 709)
      - "Recuerdos de Bibliotecas Norteamericanas:"manuscript, 1961 Apr 18 (Box 27, Folder 710)
    - Susan H. Vernon: clippings, tributes, 1910-52; undated (Box 27, Folder 711)
    - Miscellaneous, clippings; tributes; 1906-61 (Box 27, Folder 712)
  - Reminiscences
    - Interviews with alumnae and staff: transcripts and notes, 1967-75; undated (Box 27, Folder 713)
    - "Memoria del Cursillo de Bibliotecarias", 1949 (Box 27, Folder 714)
    - Questionnaire to Antiquismas Alumnas del Instituto Internacional, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 715)
  - Memorabilia
    - Buildings
      - Floor and garden plans, 1917; 1975 (Box 27, Folder 716)
      - Inventories, 1923; 1955 (Box 27, Folder 717)
    - Certificates and diplomas, undated (Box 27, Folder 718)
    - Guest book, 1913-61 (Box 27, Folder 719)
    - Hymns, poems, and songs, 1896; 1902 (Box 27, Folder 720)
    - Invitations and programs, 1883-1910 (Box 27, Folder 721-722)
    - Invitations and programs, 1913-75; undated (Box 28, Folder 723)
    - Logo, undated (Box 28, Folder 724)
    - Miscellaneous, 1874-1968; undated (Box 28, Folder 725-726)
    - Activities of the Corporation in US: announcements, invitations, and programs, 1900-39; undated (Box 28, Folder 727-728)
    - Report cards, 1889-1910 (Box 28, Folder 729)
    - Scrapbooks, photo albums, drawings of the Institute, 1893-1977; undated (Box 29)
    - Historical Materials and Memorabilia (Box 30)
- Series V. LEGAL
  This series consists of major legal documents in the history of the Institute arranged chronologically. Included are agreements and leases with the Spanish government and the US Department of State, material on bequests to the Institute, building sales, changes in by-laws, and personnel complaints.
  - Papers of incorporation of IIGS, 1892 (Box 31, Folder 730)
  - Homer Lockwood bequest, 1895; 1915-16 (Box 31, Folder 731)
  - Florence Sanborn bequest, 1905; undated (Box 31, Folder 732)
  - Power of attorney, Susan Huntington, 1912 (Box 31, Folder 733)
  - Agreements between the IIGS and the Junta para Ampliacion de Estudios e Investigaciones Cientficas, 1918-24 (Box 31, Folder 734)
  - Sale of Building at Fortuny 53, 1919-25; undated (Box 31, Folder 735)
  - Leases with Junta para Ampliacion de Estudios e Investigaciones Cientificas, 1919-30 (Box 31, Folder 736)
  - Power of attorney, May Gardner, 1924 (Box 31, Folder 737)
  - Instrument of Purchase and Sale for building at Fortuny 53, 1927 (Box 31, Folder 738)
  - Power of attorney, Mary Sweeney, 1940 (Box 31, Folder 739)
  - Contract with Instituto de Espana, 1941 (Box 31, Folder 740)
  - Agreement with U.S. Department of State, 1944 (Box 31, Folder 741)
  - Leases with Coleglo-Estudio, 1950-67 (Box 31, Folder 742)
  - Agreement with US Department of State, 1951 (Box 31, Folder 743)
  - Application to Ministry of Education for recognition as an educational institution, 1962 (Box 31, Folder 744)
  - Power of attorney, Dorothy N. Marshall, 1975; undated (Box 31, Folder 745)
  - Brief re firing of Ilene Avery, 1978 (Box 31, Folder 746)
  - Opinion on complaint brought by librarians, 1978 (Box 31, Folder 747)
  - Revocation of power of attorney, Ilene Avery, 1978 (Box 31, Folder 748)
  - Claim on Fortuny 53, 1978-79; undated (Box 31, Folder 749)
  - By-law changes, 1980 (Box 31, Folder 750)
- Series VI. LIBRARY
  This series is made up of acquisitions lists and notes and miscellaneous papers pertaining to the maintenance of the IIGS library.
  - Acquisitions lists, 1957-78; undated (Box 31, Folder 751-752)
  - Accession book, 1956-66 (Box 31, Folder 753)
  - Ultimas Adquisiciones [published list], 1952-79 (Box 31, Folder 754-757)
  - Rules for the organization of the Library and Children's Library, 1929; 1956 (Box 31, Folder 758)
- Series VII. LISTS
  This series is made up of lists of students, staff, and corporators of the Institute filed chronologically and the card file listing of IIGS records made by Enriqueta Martin in the early 1970s.
  The card file is arranged according to Martin's file (carpeta) numbers.
  - Miscellaneous: clippings and notes, undated (Box 31, Folder 759)
  - Alumnae/students, 1935-1968 (Box 31, Folder 760)
  - Committees of the Corporation, undated (Box 31, Folder 761)
  - Directors and Members of the Corporation, 1913; 1936-64 (Box 31, Folder 762-764)
  - Directors and Members of the Corporation, 1965-74; undated (Box 32, Folder 765-768)
  - Staff, yearly, 1911-78 (Box 32, Folder 769)
  - Staff, compilation, 1908; 1967 (Box 32, Folder 770)
  - Supporters and associates, 1936; 1967 (Box 32, Folder 771)
  - Guide to Enriqueta Martin's card files, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 772)
  - Card files - Membership
    - Special donations, 1915-29 (Box 33)
    - Mailing list, 1922 (Box 33)
    - Resigned and deceased, 1914-39 (Box 33)
    - Advisory Council, undated (Box 33)
    - Memorial and Life Members, 1915-30 (Box 33)
    - Corporators, 1939-65 (Box 33)
    - Directors and Corporators, 1912-45 (Box 33)
    - Staff and Active Members, 1945-65 (Box 33)
  - Card files - Enriqueta Martin
    - Carpeta nos. 1-17, 1973 (Box 34)
    - Carpeta nos. 18-59, 1973 (Box 35)
    - Curso de 1974-75, 1973 (Box 35)
    - Alphabetical index to filing system, 1973 (Box 35)
- Series VIII. MINUTES, AGENDAS, AND CALLS TO MEETINGS
  This series consists of incomplete sets of minutes of the major governing groups of the IIGS Corporation in the U.S., some of the Corporation's committees, and some groups of Institute staff.
  The material is arranged by committee or group and filed chronologically. Within each group, where such material occurs, agendas and calls to meetings are filed in a separate chronological sequence.
  - Board of Directors and Corporators
    - Agendas and calls to meetings, 1915-80; undated (Box 36, Folder 773-774)
    - Minutes, 1895-1957 (Box 36, Folder 775-782)
    - Minutes, 1958-85; undated (Box 37, Folder 783-801)
    - Notes on minutes by Enriqueta Martin, 1912-16 (Box 37, Folder 802)
  - Executive and Liaison Committees
    - Agendas and calls to meetings, 1951-65 (Box 37, Folder 803-804)
    - Minutes, 1915-17, 1950-82 (Box 38, Folder 805-811)
  - Discussion Group on future of IIGS, 1962 (Box 38, Folder 812)
  - English Department Teachers: minutes, 1958-67 (Box 38, Folder 813-816)
  - Estudio English Teachers: minutes, 1960-61 (Box 38, Folder 817)
  - English Program Committee: minutes, 1963-65 (Box 38, Folder 818)
  - Junta Asesora [Advisory Group]: minutes, 1969-78 (Box 38, Folder 819-820)
  - Library Staff: minutes, 1947; 1961-78 (Box 38, Folder 821)
  - Miscellaneous, committees and groups, 1922-79 (Box 38, Folder 822)
- Series IX. PERSONNEL
  This series consists of forms, receipts, and certificates on personnel, plus curriculum vitae for staff, student assistants, and participants in the IIGS Foreign Scholars Program.
  The forms, receipts, and certificates are arranged chronologically. The curriculum vitae are arranged alphabetically.
  - General: forms, receipts, certificates, 1946-63; undated (Box 38, Folder 823-824)
  - Curriculum vitae, A-Z, 1955-65; undated (Box 38, Folder 825-826)
- Series X. PHOTOGRAPHS
  This series consists of photographs, negatives and slides, each filed separately. The photographs and negatives are divided into six parallel sections by subject: Buildings, Events, Staff, Students, Affiliated Organizations and Programs, and Miscellaneous.
  The slides, which appear to have been made to accompany a talk on the history of the Institute (n.d.), are arranged chronologically.
  - Buildings
    - Fortuny 53 (original in Madrid), 1901; 1922 (Box 39, Folder 827)
    - Miguel Angel 8 (Alice Gordon Gulick Memorial Hall) (Box 39)
      - Exteriors, general, 1910; 1951-56 (Box 39, Folder 828-829)
      - Exteriors, garden, 1970-71; undated (Box 39, Folder 830)
      - Interiors, general, 1951-59; undated (Box 39, Folder 831-832)
      - Interiors, Director's suite, 1958-60; undated (Box 39, Folder 833-834)
      - Interiors, hall and staircase, 1915; 1951 (Box 39, Folder 835)
      - Interiors, library, 1912-70; undated (Box 39, Folder 836-837)
      - Interiors, children's library, 1936-69; undated (Box 39, Folder 838)
  - Events
    - Miscellaneous, 1953-72; undated (Box 39, Folder 839)
    - Christmas Party, 1950-62; undated (Box 39, Folder 840)
    - Dramatics, 1913; 1957-59 (Box 39, Folder 841-842)
    - Graduation, 1951-63 (Box 39, Folder 843-845)
    - Halloween party, 1958-63 (Box 39, Folder 846-847)
    - Party for Dorothy Marshall, 1971 (Box 39, Folder 848)
    - Welcoming Party, 1957-62 (Box 40, Folder 849-851)
    - Trips, 1921-71; undated (Box 40, Folder 852-853)
  - Staff
    - Miscellaneous, 1915-70; undated (Box 40, Folder 854)
    - Groups, 1944-66; undated (Box 40, Folder 855)
    - English department, 1970-72; undated (Box 40, Folder 856)
    - Library, 1934-72; undated (Box 40, Folder 857)
    - Alice Gordon Gulick, William Booker Gulick, 1871; 1875 (Box 40, Folder 858)
    - Enriqueta Martin, 1924-61; undated (Box 40, Folder 859)
    - Mary Sweeney, 1932-56; undated (Box 40, Folder 860)
    - Directors and Corporators, 1930-56; undated (Box 40, Folder 861)
  - Students
    - Groups, 1880-1933; undated (Box 40, Folder 862)
    - Classes, general, 1914-15; 1969-70; undated (Box 40, Folder 863)
    - Classes, English department, 1957-61 (Box 40, Folder 864)
    - Classes, library science, 1936-70 (Box 40, Folder 865)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Alumnae, 1954; undated (Box 40, Folder 866)
    - Book of photos, 1951 (Box 40, Folder 867)
    - General and unidentified, 1875-1961 (Box 40, Folder 868-869)
  - Affiliated Organizations and Programs
    - Antiquas Alumnas del Instituto Internacional, 1971 (Box 40, Folder 870)
    - Asociacion de Diplomados del Instituto Internacional, 1956-57 (Box 40, Folder 871)
    - Colegio Internacional para Senoritas, 1915; undated (Box 40, Folder 872)
    - Colegio Estudio
      - Miscellaneous, 1967; undated (Box 40, Folder 873)
      - Classes, 1950; undated (Box 40, Folder 874)
      - Dramatics, 1950-74 (Box 41, Folder 875-876)
      - Picture books, 1951 (Box 41, Folder 878)
    - Colonia Pax, 1939-40 (Box 41, Folder 879)
    - Instituto Escuela, 1924; undated (Box 41, Folder 880)
    - Residencia de Senoritas, 1919; 1936 (Box 41, Folder 881)
    - Third Year Programs, 1958-62; undated (Box 41, Folder 882)
    - Slide list (Box 41, Folder 883)
    - Glass plate negatives (3) (Box 41, Folder 884)
  - Negatives, with prints (Box 41)
    - Buildings (Box 42)
    - Events, Staff (Box 43)
    - Students, Miscellaneous, Affiliated Organizations and Programs (Box 44)
  - Negatives, no prints (Box 45)
    - Slides (Box 46)
- Series XI. PUBLICATIONS
  This series is made up of newsletters, published reports, catalogs, and historical and informational pamphlets published by staff and students of the Institute in Spain or by the Corporation in the U.S. The scrapbooks in Series IV contain issues of publications not available in this series.
  The material is arranged in two sections as follows: named series are filed by title, and other items are filed by type of publication.
  - Annual Reports, 1901-22 (Box 47, Folder 885-889)
  - Bulletins, 1903-11; 1968 (Box 47, Folder 890-892)
  - By-Laws of the Directors, 1908; 1916; 1952 (Box 47, Folder 893)
  - English Department Bulletin, 1968-76 (Box 47, Folder 894-896)
  - E.E.C. Mews, 1959-60 (Box 47, Folder 897)
  - La Generacion del 78, Mar, 1978? (Box 47, Folder 898)
  - Institute News, 1955-62 (Box 47, Folder 899-903)
  - Institute News, 1962-64 (Box 48, Folder 904-905)
  - Letter from Spain, 1884-85 (Box 48, Folder 906)
  - Newsletter, 1969-71 (Box 48, Folder 907)
  - Notes and News, 1922-65 (Box 48, Folder 908-910)
  - Report of a Public Meeting of the Officers and Friends of the IIGS, 1903; 1911 (Box 48, Folder 911)
  - Yellow, Red, White and Blue, 1915 (Box 48, Folder 912)
  - Histories, 1907-1986 (Box 48, Folder 913)
  - Reprints, 1910-37 (Box 48, Folder 914)
  - Fund-raising pamphlets, 1891-1910 (Box 48, Folder 915)
  - Informational pamphlets and brochures, 1892-1920 (Box 48, Folder 916-917)
- Series XII. REPORTS
  This series consists of unpublished reports prepared by Institute staff, committees, advisory and affiliated groups, directors, and corporators, filed chronologically. Reports that were clearly designated as intended for meetings of the Board or its committees, or were entered into the minutes, are filed with the minutes (Series VIII). Reports that were published are filed in Series XI - Publications. Similar material can be found throughout the files of the Corresponding Secretary in Series II.
  - 1881-82 through 1957-58 (Box 48, Folder 918-933)
  - 1958-59 through 1965-66 (Box 49, Folder 934-954)
  - 1966-67 through 1980, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 955-978)
- Series XIII. SPEECHES
  This series consists of texts of seven speeches given at Institute or Corporation gatherings.
  - "Behind the Headlines from Spain," Saville Davis, 24 Feb 1939 (Box 51, Folder 979)
  - Commencement Address, 1896 (Box 51, Folder 980)
  - Commencement Address, [Joan Connelly ?], 3 Jun 1961 (Box 51, Folder 981)
  - Commencement Address, Mary Sweeney, Jun 1962 (Box 51, Folder 982)
  - Commencement Address, [Joan Appel ?], 8 Jun 1963 (Box 51, Folder 983)
  - Service in Memory of Jean Betty Bratton,Ilene Avery, 23 Oct 1973 (Box 51, Folder 984)
  - "Welcome to all of you.. .", undated (Box 51, Folder 985)
- Series XIV. STUDENT PAPERS
  This series is made up of papers in Spanish and/or English written by Institute students as part of their course work. They are arranged by title. Paper topics include: the history of the Institute, reports of IIGS activities, women's education, education in Spain, library science, and current events.
  - "Alice Gordon Gulick: The Pioneer," Esther Perez de King, 1953 (Box 51, Folder 986)
  - "An American Pioneer in Spain", undated (Box 51, Folder 987)
  - "The Arrival at the International Institute," Esther, Perez de King undated (Box 51, Folder 988)
  - "The Art Class," Esther Perez de King, undated (Box 51, Folder 989)
  - "Art in General Education," Maria de las Nieves Largacha, Oct 1958 (Box 51, Folder 990)
  - "A Birthday Greeting," Esther Perez de King, undated (Box 51, Folder 991)
  - "Bodas Reales," Esther Perez de King, undated (Box 51, Folder 992)
  - "The Christmas Play," Esther Perez de King, undated (Box 51, Folder 993)
  - "Classes on Librarianship in the Provinces", undated (Box 51, Folder 994)
  - "Cornwall: Un Estudio Bibliotecario," Josefina R. Sanjuro Salgado, 1959 (Box 51, Folder 995)
  - "Compleavos Feliz," Esther Perez de King, undated (Box 51, Folder 996)
  - "Curso de Verano Para Bibliotecarios en la Ciudad de Birmingham," E. Verdia Maceiros, 1955 (Box 51, Folder 997)
  - "Escape," Esther Perez de King, undated (Box 51, Folder 998)
  - "Escuela Superior del Magisterio," Maria Rosa Urabayen, 1914? (Box 51, Folder 999)
  - "Espana," Judith Brinkerhoff, Jan 1958 (Box 51, Folder 1000)
  - "Friends and Neighbors,"Esther Perez de King, undated (Box 51, Folder 1001)
  - "La Funcion de Navidad," Esther Perez de King, undated (Box 51, Folder 1002)
  - "The Gables," Jose Ausorus, undated (Box 51, Folder 1003)
  - Graduation, undated (Box 51, Folder 1004)
  - "Guantes Blancos," Esther Perez de King, undated (Box 51, Folder 1005)
  - "Habia.. ." Iva Felipe Orejon, undated (Box 51, Folder 1006)
  - "Happy Birthday", undated (Box 51, Folder 1007)
  - "How She Raised Money for the Institute,", undated (Box 51, Folder 1008)
  - "Impressiones y Ensenanzas Obtenidas en el Viaje Realizado a Paris para Estudiar la Organizacion y Funcionamiento de Algunas Bibliotecas - Memoria," Maria Rodriguez Gomez, Oct. 7, 1956 (Box 51, Folder 1009)
  - "The Institucion Libre de Ensenanza," Esther Perez de King, undated (Box 51, Folder 1010)
  - "Llegada al Instituto," Esther Perez de King (Box 51, Folder 1011)
  - "Luncheon at the Embassy," Esther Perez de King, undated (Box 51, Folder 1012)
  - "Luz de Mes Ojos," Esther Perez de King, undated (Box 51, Folder 1013)
  - "Memoria," Dolores Corrons Rodriguez, undated (Box 51, Folder 1014)
  - "La Mujer en Espana, 186C-1960,", undated (Box 51, Folder 1015)
  - "My Scholarship in Cambridge," Maria del Carmen Gil Fernandez, Nov 1, 1956 (Box 51, Folder 1016)
  - "A Night at the Opera," Esther Perez de King, undated (Box 51, Folder 1017)
  - "Papa Visits the Institute," Esther Perez de King, undated (Box 51, Folder 1018)
  - "La Profesora de Frances", undated (Box 51, Folder 1019)
  - La Profesora de Gimnasia, undated (Box 51, Folder 1020)
  - "La Profesora de Labores,", undated (Box 51, Folder 1021)
  - "El Profesor de Musica - Report," Gloria Muniz, undated (Box 51, Folder 1022)
  - Report, Gloria Muniz, undated (Box 51, Folder 1023)
  - "Royal Wedding" Esther Perez de King, undated (Box 51, Folder 1024)
  - "A Spanish Burro at the English Embassy," Esther Perez de King, undated (Box 51, Folder 1025)
  - "The Spanish Carnival," Esther Perez de King, undated (Box 51, Folder 1026)
  - "The Spanish Faculty," Esther Perez de King, undated (Box 51, Folder 1027)
  - "The Story of the Instituto Escuela," Esther Perez de King, undated (Box 51, Folder 1028)
  - "A Trip to E1 Escarral," Esther Perez de King, undated (Box 51, Folder 1029)
  - The Tumbola, undated (Box 51, Folder 1030)
  - "Two Months in London," Marien Rivera, 1955 (Box 51, Folder 1031)
  - "University of Leicester - Vacation Course," Maria de las Nieves Largacha, 1958 (Box 51, Folder 1332)
  - "Una Visita al Teatro Real," Esther Perez de King (Box 51, Folder 1033)
  - "Voyage to England," Carmen Castilla, 1950 (Box 51, Folder 1034)
  - "White Gloves," Esther Perez de King, undated (Box 51, Folder 1035)
  - Wornen's Education Outside the Institute, undated (Box 51, Folder 1036)
- Series XV. AFFILIATED AND RELATED ORGANIZATIONS
  This series consists of circulars, clippings, correspondence, memorabilia, minutes, reports, and miscellaneous papers produced by organizations affiliated with but not sponsored by the Institute. Groups represented include alumnae organizations, educational groups with which the IIGS collaborated, and groups that rented space in the IIGS building (s).
  The material is arranged by organization name.
  - Anitiguas Alumnas del Instituto Internacional: letter, list, undated (Box 52, Folder 1037)
  - Asociacion de Diplomados del Instituto Internacional
    - Correspondence, 1950-61; undated (Box 52, Folder 1038)
    - Legal: constitution, regulations, 1950-56; undated (Box 52, Folder 1039)
    - Membership lists, 1956-57; undated (Box 52, Folder 1040)
    - Minutes, 1956-57 (Box 52, Folder 1041)
    - Reports, 1950-63; undated (Box 52, Folder 1042)
    - Scholarship: announcements, 1955-64; undated (Box 52, Folder 1043)
    - Speech on the History of the Asociacion by Josefina Sanchez-Pedreno, 13 May 1950 (Box 52, Folder 1044)
    - Programs, announcements, clippings, 1950-55; undated (Box 52, Folder 1045)
  - Scrapbooks, 1948-68
    - Ciclo Cultural Politeia, 1970-76 (Box 53, Folder 1046)
    - Colegio Estudio, 1954-66; undated (Box 53, Folder 1047)
    - Colegio Internacional, 1907-86; undated (Box 53, Folder 1048)
    - Colonia Pax, 1939-41 (Box 53, Folder 1049)
    - Instituto-Escuela de secunda ensenanza, 1923-29; 1978 (Box 53, Folder 1050)